# Gleb Mazovetskiy

Hildestraße 13 13089 Berlin, Germany glex.spb@gmail.com http://blog.glebm.com +34 620.628.683

### **PROFILE**

I am passionate about business, entrepreneurship, and science. I am also an experienced software developer. I work on a number of open source projects that you can see on my Github profile. I have been doing startups for 6 years, filling many non-technical roles from marketing to accounting.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Co-founder at Itbyen 2014-Present

Building a job portal platform for creating industry and country- specific job portals, targeting long tail. The first portal on the platform targets Norwegian IT job market.

# Lead Developer at Zuigo 2013

I was building a platform to organize, discover, and book local events.

# Lead Developer at Just Landed 2009-2013

I built a content aggregation system processing hundreds of thousands of job and housing offers daily, an ad delivery platform serving dynamic content user-tailored ads, and worked on business critical tasks and on performance of our high-traffic web application.

### Co-founder at iOrder SL 2009-2011

I built the technology for nightclubs to promote social interaction and to find out what music the audience wants most.

### Java Developer at Devexperts 2008-2009

I built a library to draw and slice and dice financial prediction models in 3D during my time as intern at Devexperts, using OpenGL in Java via JOGL.

# Web Developer at St. Louis University, Madrid Campus 2008-2009 I developed web applications for faculty and staff at St. Louis University

### **EDUCATION**

# Saint Louis University, Madrid Campus 2008-2012

Undergraduate, International Business. Head of Mathematics club.

### Youth Mathematician's School, St Petersburg, Russia 2006-2008

Advanced studies and research in pure mathematics.

### AWARDS

# VII Kolmogorov's Readings, Mathematics May 2007

Awarded 1st place in Mathematics section for a paper on Classifying totalistic deterministic cellular automata rules on a thorus, co-author Eugene Bakisov.

VIII Russian-wide school team programming olympics November 2007 Our team won a 2nd diploma in the Russian-wide team programming contest, an ACM-type competition.

### SKILLS IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

I started programming at 11, writing algorithms for contest-type problems in Pascal, C, and then Java. At my first job at Devexperts I wrote a component for drawing 3D stock market charts in Java for a stock trading platform desktop application. After, I became interested in web development and discovered Ruby and Ruby on Rails framework. Since then I've worked on high-traffic web applications, and handled the stack from multi-stage deployment infrastructure to user interface. I am an expert in Ruby and JavaScript, and have prior experience with Java, C, Pascal, and Bash.

Some of the technologies I've worked with:

- Databases: Postgresql (proficient), MySQL (proficient), Redis (proficient), MongoDB (prior experience), Memcached (prior experience), ElasticSearch (prior experience)
- Server: Linux (proficient), nginx (proficient), apache (prior experience), heartbeat (prior experience), docker (prior experience)
- Version control: git (proficient), svn (prior experience)
- Web Backend: Ruby on Rails (proficient), Node.js (beginner)
- Web Frontend: Expert knowledge of HTML (Slim, Haml), CSS (Sass, LESS, Stylus), and JavaScript (CoffeeScript). Both traditional websites and and single page applications with AngularJS.
- Communication: JSON (expert), XML (prior experience), XSLT. Experience in setting up DNS, SSL, SSH.

### OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Some of my notable open source projects, more on <a href="https://github.com/glebm">https://github.com/glebm</a>:

- <u>bootstrap-sass</u> is an automatically generated port of Twitter Bootstrap framework to Sass. It started off as a 3-rd party project but has now become the official Sass port.
- <u>i18n-tasks</u> is a static analyzer for Ruby i18n (internationalization) library. It helps find and manage missing and unused translations.
- <u>order query</u> is an ActiveRecord ORM extension that finds ordered database records adjacent to a given efficiently, using an OFFSET-less approach.